# BEAU HODES

## CONTACT

BEAUHODES@GMAIL.COM BEAUHODES.COM

## **PROFILE**

Researcher and software developer specifically interested in blockchain/DeFi applications and scaling, trading/market research, and fintech products with the goal of finding creative business solutions for new technology. I am a very quick, motivated learner who thrives in a fast-paced environment and enjoys complex problem solving.

## EDUCATION

## BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE MAY 2021

Solidity/EVM

Hardhat/Foundry

• JavaScript/Node.js

• Cloud: GCP/Azure

• Data Structures/Algorithms

UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS | LAWRENCE, KS GPA: 3.90 MAJOR, 3.83 OVERALL ACT: 33

## SKILLS

- Python
- C++/C
- Git
- Excel/Office
- SQL
- HTML/CSS

## **PROJECTS**

### NFT LOTTERY

JANUARY 2022

 Solidity implementation and tests for an NFT lottery game where sellers can deposit NFTs and users can deposit tokens for a chance to win the NFT. Not used in production for legal reasons.

#### **ALERT BOTS**

2021-2022

 Use Python, JavaScript, and various APIs to send out alerts for trading volume spikes, Twitter follows, and trending searches.

## PERSONAL SPEECH TRAINER

IN PROGRESS

• Uses a respiratory sensor and Python to help those who stutter, including myself, work on their fluency using computer visuals.

#### **PROGMON**

NOVEMBER 2019

 Along with 4 classmates, created a basic fighting game, called Progmon, using Python and Pygame. My responsibilities included game flow design, computer logic, test suite development, and graphic design.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **CO-FOUNDER & RESEARCHER**

UPNOW CRYPTO RESEARCH | SEPTEMBER 2021-CURRENT

- UpNow Crypto Research is a firm dedicated to providing in-depth market research, insights, and education to anyone interested in cryptocurrencies and crypto markets
- Publish bi-weekly research, market updates, and curated educational content/tutorials
- Developed website(s) and platform layouts

#### DEVELOPER

CBAL | MAY 2021 - OCTOBER 2021

- CBAi is an AI and data services startup
- Completed multiple backend integrations on behalf of clients in Node.js
- Advised on a multi-chain NFT marketplace and an AI-based price prediction model
- Wrote the initial backend architecture for an NFT marketplace

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN**

PORT TMS | MAY 2019 - NOVEMBER 2019

- Port TMS is a cloud-based transportation management software company founded in 2018
- General programmer; implemented, from back end to front end, a web interface for company developers to save time in the creation and management customer data reports

#### KU LEADERSHIP CHALLENGE

JANUARY 2020

 Two day seminar promoting leadership skills and networking sponsored by corporate affiliates

#### OTHER RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

- Backend Developer at Clear Contracts, 2021-2022
- Operations Intern at Lockton Companies, 2020
- Data Analytics Consultant at Astra Innovations, 2019-2020
- Web Designer at Midland Metal, 2017

## CERTIFICATES

#### CRYPTOCURRENCY AND BLOCKCHAIN

UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA (ONLINE) | JANUARY 2021

SEQUENCES, TIME SERIES, AND PREDICITON IN TENSORFLOW DEEPLEARNING.AI | AUGUST 2020

#### **BLOOMBERG MARKET CONCEPTS**

BLOOMBERG LP | APRIL 2020

#### IBM DATA SCIENCE PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

COURSERA/IBM | SEPTEMBER 2019

 Nine-course certificate using Python and various algorithms

MICROSOFT: AZURE207X —"DATABASES IN AZURE" EDX | MARCH 2019

## SELECTED COURSEWORK

- Software Engineering: Systematic development of software products including life-cycle models, teams, tools, testing, planning, and estimating. Also covered Agile development and Git version-control.
- Others: Computer Algorithms, Data Structures, Compiler Construction, Machine Learning, Computer Security, Calculus I-III, Linear Algebra, Statistics, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture, Databases, Computer Forensics